<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[cJaredm Dev Blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[Dev thoughts and mistakes.]]></description><link>https://cjaredm.github.io</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 17:58:03 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Level Playing Field]]></title><description><![CDATA[Published: May 29, 2019 Read this with a grain of salt. It’s how I feel, so put your pitch fork down. I know that this isn’t 100% accurate…]]></description><link>https://cjaredm.github.io/2019-05-15-deployed/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cjaredm.github.io/2019-05-15-deployed/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Published: May 29, 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read this with a grain of salt. It’s how I feel, so put your pitch fork down. I know that this isn’t 100% accurate and there are cases you could point at that prove that. Calm down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What do the l33t use?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently was talking to someone I’ve been teaching/mentoring. He was curious about the tools and methods I was showing him on how to make a web page. He assumed these tools and methods were not what the the professionals use, so he wanted to see how I actually do things.
As I was explaining things I realized, maybe not for the first time, that in my field, Frontend Development, we all basically are on the same level playing field. Free tools, open source libraries, all available to everyone, n00bs and l33ts the same (l33t is kinda annoying but it gets the point across).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Code/Frameworks/Libraries&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you want to write a book. What do you need, and is there anything you have to pay for? Well, you need to know the language you’re writing in. You need something to write on to save it… You get the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to write some code or a program or whatever? Do you know the language? Guess what, it’s free. You don’t technically need to pay someone to teach you (though it can help). You don’t need to pay for a certificate or diploma. You don’t need to pay to gain access to the language or documentation on how to use it. It’s free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JavaScript/HTML/CSS, it’s all free and wildly documented all over the internet. You can make a webpage on your computer this moment using any text editor in like two minutes. Using any computer, anywhere. Nothing stopping anyone from doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies build things to help themselves and make it available free to the world. Facebook created React, a library for JavaScript that makes building interactive sites so easy. It’s just JavaScript but with pre-written helpers that you use to speed things up. Technically you could not use React and just use JavaScript to do the exact same thing, but React is easier and faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AirBnB made some JavaScript testing tools. Other people make tools and just publish for everyone to use. Things like EsLint, Prettier, lodash, styled-components. All free for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Editors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several free code editors out there. Do you need one? Nope., but think of the difference writing a paper for school in the basic text editor on your computer versus using Microsoft Word. Word picks up on spelling errors and shows them to you. It has all kinds of editing options and tools specific for writing documents that a normal plain text editor doesn’t have. Same goes for writing code. Technically you could use Vim, the text editor built i to your terminal(command line) on your computer. But that would be hell! So people made editors specific to the languages of code you write in to be able to pick up on mistakes and makes writing faster and easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two big ones are VS Code and Sublime Text. I follow Wes Bos fairly closely, he makes awesome tutorials for JavaScript and React. Because he does tutorials for anyone wanting to learn he wants to make the learning focused on the topic, not the tools, and doesn’t want you to have you to have to pay for extra stuff, which is why he uses VS Code. Very awesome free editor. Very good for paid programming since you can collaborate on  specific project with someone anywhere else in the world. I’ve used it a few times and it has been awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At my work they pay for us to use WebStorm and PhpStorm, editors made by JetBrains. I found that because I have a masters degree my college gives my my .edu email for life. It so happens that the easier way to prove you are a student is to have a .edu email from a big college and that means student discounts or free stuff. I have WebStorm for free with their student program. It does a few things the free editors can’t or haven’t added yet, but VS Code is adding things all the time and can do many things WebStorm can’t. The idea is that, it doesn’t matter though. I don’t need to pay for an editor to code something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Version Control / Backups&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing code is basically just some text documents, usually doesn’t take up a lot of storage on your computer. But, it’s a good idea to keep it somewhere accessible and saved off your computer. You might think of other storage places like DropBox and GoogleDrive but that may eventually cost you as well, as you make a lot of projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In comes places like GitHub and GitBucket and another one… git labs maybe? They use command line interface (CLI) which, you guessed it, is free, called git. Git is used for version control and backing things up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While writing a paper for school have you saved it (KittensPaper) duplicated it and made changes to the duplicate? Then you save that with a different name, like  FinalKittensPaper. You are versioning your papers. Labeling them to help and making duplicates in case one is deleted or corrupted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is what git does,  but for code. It lets you keep the good code on a branch while you make a new branch to try changing that code. If you changes are good you can merge them into the good branch and do it again. And those places like GitHub make it so you can save them online, for free, and show them to others and even have others use your code in their projects. That is where you can download all those libraries I was talking about earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;More than one way to skin a cat&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another awesome thing about programming is that you can create the same thing in a myriad of ways. You can use differe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some ways may be worse/better than others  but that is the idea. You can do it your own way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s amazing that any computer right now could be used to create just about anything in code. You could download some free software, like code editors to make it easier,  but you don’t have to. You could use some libraries other people have written for free,  but you don’t have to. You can save it online for free, but you don’t have to. Right now you can code anything anyone else could code, you could create any website just like any other company or person could, in the world. The only difference is what you and they know about programming languages, which again, you could learn for free online. We developers are on a level playing field. It is awesome to know I can pick up any language I desire at any time. I can make a website just as good as a big corporation, if I had the motivation to. I am the only thing stopping me from learning how.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Deployed!]]></title><description><![CDATA[Finally! I deployed my first ever version 1 project. I’ve started
many projects before but hadn’t pushed thru to get them published and live…]]></description><link>https://cjaredm.github.io/2019-05-29-side-projects/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cjaredm.github.io/2019-05-29-side-projects/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Finally! I deployed my first ever version 1 project. I’ve started
many projects before but hadn’t pushed thru to get them published and live.
This time I did it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/pVM4xuseBY0oIcK2Yp/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;I did it!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What’s the story?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year I had been looking for projects to build, maybe something that would
end up making me money. I asked several family and friends for ideas. I
listened to podcasts about side hustles and these types of projects, or
start-ups. I found that most often they stumble into a good business idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance there was a story of a company making software for plumbers to
find customers. They made a great project and had businesses trying to
use them but many were back out and disappear. They decided to look into how
these businesses were using their product. They found that these small
businesses were struggling with other things and would end up bailing on
their product or not giving it enough attention. Their main issue was
organizing themselves and tracking paper work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The business pivoted and focused on helping small businesses with their
paperwork and tracking. They became a huge success after stumbling onto
the need of their customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what I was trying to do. I found a friend that has a manufacturing
business as a machine shop machining parts from metals. He told me they
have poor order/part tracking and would love to have something simple.
Of course that kind of software already exists but not specific to his
industry that also doesn’t have a ton of things he doesn’t want to pay for.
I worked on it for the last 3-4 months and finally deployed a week ago!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is it?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I built a a customized version of a kanban board specific to his shop/industry.
Pretty simple at first glance, a drag and drop list of todos with specific
machines to do them on and a finished section. I built on that idea and
features as I went. Soon I’ll have analytics built in so that he can look
back and see what employees are working the most efficiently, what customers
provide the most profits, what parts are loosing them money, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./Job_Tracker.png&quot; alt=&quot;I did it!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He already started showing his team and will start utilizing it next week.
Because it was a success he brought me another idea of an app to build for
his sisters company that they’ll pay for in full, where this current project
I own and will be charging for monthly and start selling to other shops.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How I Got Started]]></title><description><![CDATA[TLDR I got degrees in things that gave me debt and no real job I loved. Got sick, literally sick, at my job and
decided it was time to…]]></description><link>https://cjaredm.github.io/2019-04-24-how-i-got-started/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cjaredm.github.io/2019-04-24-how-i-got-started/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h4&gt;TLDR&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got degrees in things that gave me debt and no real job I loved. Got sick, literally sick, at my job and
decided it was time to figure something out. A friend mentored me and within 4 months I got my first dev job!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/a9327ff8fbcb588a4384b5d10371150a/48a11/getajobmeme.jpg&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
  
  &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
    style=&quot;position: relative; display: block;  max-width: 500px; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
      style=&quot;padding-bottom: 66.60000000000001%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAANABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFgABAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAwAE/8QAFQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQL/2gAMAwEAAhADEAAAAczA81jik//EABkQAAMBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAECAxESAP/aAAgBAQABBQIFy3eh6HqdN8xxaNrf/8QAFBEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEP/aAAgBAwEBPwE//8QAFBEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEP/aAAgBAgEBPwE//8QAGBAAAwEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAARARADH/2gAIAQEABj8CE4wJqv/EABoQAQEBAAMBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAERACExUWH/2gAIAQEAAT8hUlfUMJOfhcJBePcoi61QZrodTf/aAAwDAQACAAMAAAAQBx//xAAWEQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABEGH/2gAIAQMBAT8QXJ//xAAYEQACAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAREhQf/aAAgBAgEBPxBKdKP/xAAbEAEAAwEBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAABABEhMXFBof/aAAgBAQABPxC4dI4qeI+TgUtDb7zYORMUAT8jKIBtvwuKQ32VsECS9n//2Q==&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 100%; margin: 0; vertical-align: middle; position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; box-shadow: inset 0px 0px 0px 400px white;&quot;
        alt=&quot;Get A Job meme&quot;
        title=&quot;&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/a9327ff8fbcb588a4384b5d10371150a/48a11/getajobmeme.jpg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/a9327ff8fbcb588a4384b5d10371150a/8ee9c/getajobmeme.jpg 148w,
/static/a9327ff8fbcb588a4384b5d10371150a/ebbe7/getajobmeme.jpg 295w,
/static/a9327ff8fbcb588a4384b5d10371150a/48a11/getajobmeme.jpg 500w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px&quot;
      /&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Extended History&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent a bunch of money I didn’t have and received a BA in Philosophy. It was fun!
Learned to think more logically and get new perspective… BUT didn’t get me a job. Still fun though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that I got married, had a kid and decided that maybe… maybe I should do something to
make enough money for a family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loved learning and wished I could just keep going to college etc. So what I decided was to
get a master’s degree in Educational Technology, also known as Instructional Design. I’d be
able to create trainings, on everything. So I’d keep learning everything as I made different
things for different people. In fact I did some freelancing for awhile and made trainings for
pest control technicians, an online MBA program in Australia, and a cooking course in an
applied technical college.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUT… alas that didn’t last long. It seems that most people in my cohort in my MEd. program
already had a job in training and were getting education to move up in their company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I spent a bunch of money I didn’t have… again, to get that MEd.

  &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/657f690df4d8e1a36ca27641ffc78917/e2288/studentloanmeme.jpg&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
  
  &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
    style=&quot;position: relative; display: block;  max-width: 590px; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
      style=&quot;padding-bottom: 104.84374999999999%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAVABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAGAABAQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAMCBQT/xAAVAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAf/aAAwDAQACEAMQAAAB6cIRjtIK9GiNiv/EABoQAAMBAAMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAECAwQQEUH/2gAIAQEAAQUCaqhjqmplRapWTu746Fck2lD0dnj/xAAUEQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAg/9oACAEDAQE/AR//xAAUEQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAg/9oACAECAQE/AR//xAAdEAABBAIDAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAAIRMQMSIDKR/9oACAEBAAY/AiCVbvFs2lk6whEFauueH//EABwQAQACAgMBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEAESExEEGRUf/aAAgBAQABPyF6gkqjos+oAt6ZheGTF7jG0CqIQGrGOFQeR9h5x//aAAwDAQACAAMAAAAQTwCA/8QAFhEAAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAESAh/9oACAEDAQE/EBE//8QAFhEBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEAFB/9oACAECAQE/ENKf/8QAGxABAQADAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAREAITFRQWH/2gAIAQEAAT8QT6O7Q5e4NvNQoPRxC01ERpiCjqgBho39Pc/bfKHt5hhziG6XWOsKu3pwRgTBQK19mf/Z&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 100%; margin: 0; vertical-align: middle; position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; box-shadow: inset 0px 0px 0px 400px white;&quot;
        alt=&quot;Get A Job meme&quot;
        title=&quot;&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/657f690df4d8e1a36ca27641ffc78917/c739e/studentloanmeme.jpg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/657f690df4d8e1a36ca27641ffc78917/8ee9c/studentloanmeme.jpg 148w,
/static/657f690df4d8e1a36ca27641ffc78917/ebbe7/studentloanmeme.jpg 295w,
/static/657f690df4d8e1a36ca27641ffc78917/c739e/studentloanmeme.jpg 590w,
/static/657f690df4d8e1a36ca27641ffc78917/e2288/studentloanmeme.jpg 640w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px&quot;
      /&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also was working for Apple doing tech support part time. Eventually I did that full time… and grew to… dislike
it, to put it in nice words. It wasn’t hard, but it was boring and I didn’t fit the culture at the time. Wasn’t very
fulfilling (to me that is). I was even getting anxious and stomach aches thinking about going
to work. Dreading it every day. I wanted and needed to get out of there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During all that time I was messing around with spreadsheets and getting deeper and deeper in
Google App Script making silly things. Made a spreadsheet with birthdays that a script would
check every day around 7 AM, and text a special message I wrote to the birthday person. Super
cool, huh? I also made a spreadsheet script for emailing people to remind them when their
lease was ending, their new lease amount and other templated information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Moment&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I was having fun doing that and getting stomach aches before going to work at a dead end
job. Then BAM! My friend Kasey saw what I was doing with spreadsheets and scripts and pushed
me to learn how to code. My wife and I talked about it and I convinced her to go to work full
time while I paid a baby sitter to watch the kids while I learned how to code with some
guidance from my friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About 4 months later I won! I got a job with my friend’s company because I convinced them I
wasn’t a jerk and was a fast learner. YAY! There was probably some other technical stuff I
showed them too, but yeah. I did it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Now&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to now, 2 year later. Learned a ton more. I’m building React Native apps along
with all the other normal, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, PHP, and blah or whatever. I’ve also
found that I want to help other people. I started looking for people to help and mentor into
JavaScript. It has been fun! Met some nice people and have really enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been looking for more ways to help mentor others and keep learning. This blog will talk
about it. Keep checking in.

  &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/80f3fa8695fea9d0a4f6771204458a1b/8d2b4/iareprogrammermeme.jpg&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
  
  &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
    style=&quot;position: relative; display: block;  max-width: 474px; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
      style=&quot;padding-bottom: 74.68354430379746%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAPABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFwAAAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAMEBf/EABUBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAB/9oADAMBAAIQAxAAAAFM16ozDRF//8QAGxABAAICAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAgEDABIUITH/2gAIAQEAAQUC8c2XHHO66FjKR48Z/8QAFREBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACH/2gAIAQMBAT8BR//EABQRAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABD/2gAIAQIBAT8BP//EABwQAAIBBQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAhEhIjJhgv/aAAgBAQAGPwJwUteXZdU8lWSjfLIo5PrN2f/EAB0QAQACAgIDAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEAESExQWFxgfH/2gAIAQEAAT8hChXmGZ1K/c0oi7DuqiZcX6eIoqN0ZZ82f//aAAwDAQACAAMAAAAQpw//xAAVEQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEf/aAAgBAwEBPxBT/8QAFhEBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQBB/9oACAECAQE/EJHL/8QAHBABAAICAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQARITFBYYFR/9oACAEBAAE/EEL3EWhqz3x1FqAFh7Puo2qdByvCXkbgvCva4YrE3A9N5g5kvM//2Q==&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 100%; margin: 0; vertical-align: middle; position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; box-shadow: inset 0px 0px 0px 400px white;&quot;
        alt=&quot;Get A Job meme&quot;
        title=&quot;&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/80f3fa8695fea9d0a4f6771204458a1b/8d2b4/iareprogrammermeme.jpg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/80f3fa8695fea9d0a4f6771204458a1b/8ee9c/iareprogrammermeme.jpg 148w,
/static/80f3fa8695fea9d0a4f6771204458a1b/ebbe7/iareprogrammermeme.jpg 295w,
/static/80f3fa8695fea9d0a4f6771204458a1b/8d2b4/iareprogrammermeme.jpg 474w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 474px) 100vw, 474px&quot;
      /&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hello World! Just figured out how to setup a Gatsby Blog. First attempt at using Gatsby.
I unfortunately tried to do it the hard way, not…]]></description><link>https://cjaredm.github.io/2019-04-23-hello-world/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cjaredm.github.io/2019-04-23-hello-world/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hello World! Just figured out how to setup a Gatsby Blog. First attempt at using Gatsby.
I unfortunately tried to do it the hard way, not using the start-blog they have. Got several errors with GraphQL not finding the markdown files… lame!
So I restarted with the starter-blog and it was up and running crazy fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know this still looks like the same start-blog everyone has with Gatsby but I’ll come back and
restyle it later.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>