<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[cJaredm Dev Blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[Portfolio and Dev Blog for cJaredm]]></description><link>https://cjaredm.com</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 04:18:47 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Wordpress?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Why even talk about it? I just started a new job that is much different than my previous. I was working in 3 codebases with mostly the same…]]></description><link>https://cjaredm.com/2020-01-22-wordpress/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cjaredm.com/2020-01-22-wordpress/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 16:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;Why even talk about it?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just started a new job that is much different than my previous. I was working in 3 codebases with &lt;em&gt;mostly&lt;/em&gt; the same tech stack; now I am working on a plethora of projects in different codebases. Primary environment we work in is Wordpress. Never worked in that before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve had to come to some realizations on this because I never really wanted to work in Wordpress before, but I also never really understood Wordpress as a developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why Wordpress? Well it’s a CMS (content management system). Content as in the stuff on the pages: words, text, nav, menus, pictures, etc. As a developer I could develop any page or make content changes on the most granular level. My client that I am handing this app over too wants to make those changes In the future but they can’t make those changes without the management part of CMS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wordpress has the fundamentals setup for my clients and lets me make the granular changes too. The difference is that I can’t make a bunch of one off fixes or changes. I, as a developer, have to think of the end result and the best method for the client to manage it without me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wordpress is mostly in PHP, which is doable, but not very fun. I’ve been working in React and Gatsby and Node, etc. It has felt so free and open, at least much more than I’ve felt working in PHP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The built in building blocks of Wordpress  on the surface look and feel really nice. After using them in multiple real life situations and it gets tedious, and clunky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is only terrible documentation that gives examples out of context, and no full Wordpress site examples that are well written. It also seems that PHP developers for Wordpress are set to stay there, in PHP, not learn new ways of doings things. Yes this probably is wrong but listening to podcasts, reading tutorials and docs and watching videos has brought me to this conclusion. I just feel like Wordpress is living in the past!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can have React on the frontend! Yay! You have to use the Wordpress API though. Nay! But you can modify it and add your own endpoints! Yay! But I haven’t figured that out yet.
Most things are given to you already, like all the pages, and posts, etc. But the menus are not. You have to get a plugin, or really learn how to do it on your own so you don’t rely on all the nasty plugins. So far I’ve been successful but its been a little bit of a pain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can make your own plugins, in React! So I’ve made a plugin for a site at work to allow users to added photos and text on the photos directly in the editor layout. And move things around and it looks exactly like it would when it is rendered for the site. Much better than trying to use all these advanced custom fields and making long templates to check for rows and rows in the database. I get it, and it was easy to setup those advanced custom fields but it isn’t very intuitive to what it will look like when it is rendered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Take Aways&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wordpress feels old and it is. Feels overly and underly developed at the same time (complicated where it shouldn’t have to be, fancy features where I haven’t needed them yet). It has the ability to allow me to make some cool stuff, and make some money. I already was contacted to make a Wordpress site and get paid some nice chunk of change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worth looking into. Worth helping develop and document for other’s sakes. Worth learning and making something better.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Coding Grit]]></title><description><![CDATA[A topic has been coming up quite a bit in the last month or so for me. Boiled down to a few lines its something like: Whats the best way to…]]></description><link>https://cjaredm.com/2019-06-20-coding-grit/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cjaredm.com/2019-06-20-coding-grit/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;A topic has been coming up quite a bit in the last month or so for me. Boiled down to a few lines its something like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Whats the best way to learn to code? What should I focus on? What should I learn first?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually accompanied with mentions of that these people have been doing FreeCodeCamp or Udemy, or some type of course that hits the fundamentals of the language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How Code Courses (usually) Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These coding course online are good. They help build the foundation a coder will use to go on to build other things. This is the basis for starting to learn anything new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example: You are 4 or 5 years old and barely familiar that numbers are a thing. You’ve been told there are different numbers. So how do you learn math? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/w4AYGsSA2rK00/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Do Math&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Well you do some scaffolding. Scaffolding is the temporary structure built next to a building that helps works build up the building in safety. Its always right there, next to it and usually one level higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applied to learning it is guiding the bounds of your learning. Keeps your learning focused and always one step ahead to guide you to build on top of what you just learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance with math: learn what numbers look like, then their order, count them, learn what the mean by adding time, subtract them, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can’t jump to calculus without all those in between steps because you don’t even really know it exists or is a possibility. You need guidance on the basic parts of math before you can imagine the possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coding example with FreeCodeCamp: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You start the lessons on JavaScript. It teaches you about comments first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why?&lt;/em&gt; Because its going to be putting comments in the code and needs you to know why they are there and not breaking the code. Then it teaches you things like strings and numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why?&lt;/em&gt; Because you need to know those things to understand how variables use them. Then you can build on that with the next step. You’re building your scaffolding to support your learning, one step at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Missing Link 🔗&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scaffolding is important, can’t be skipped in some cases. But it lacks some of the most important pieces to effective learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/fFCWgjJSyY0QE/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Attention&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attention:&lt;/strong&gt; Apparently if you want to learn something you have to pay attention. In high school that meant you had to actually look up and hear the words being spoken and process them in your brain. Can’t do much of that if you’re not paying attention.
Its hard to pay attention if something is boring. Why do we think things are boring? Because… 👇&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevance&lt;/strong&gt;: Our brains have a hard time caring about things that don’t have an application in our own lives. Some people out there are good at overcoming this. Most are not.
Remember math class in high school? Someone always said: &lt;em&gt;“What is the point of learning this? I’m never going to use it.” Not relevant so I don’t care.&lt;/em&gt;
When you are wading thru all the concepts and theory of coding and only coding snippets here and there, never really putting more than a few lines together, it is hard to see what it could all lead up to. Like learning the letters of the alphabet but not understanding how they can be connected to make words and sentences and books.
I will admit doing small code challenges or completing steps in those course can be fun and feel like you’re getting really good at that language… BUT then if someone asked you to make something you have no clue on how to get started, where do you do it, how do you save it, where do people see it? You’ve learned the middle coding part but not all the parts that connect those things into a whole. Eventually you might loose… 👇&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motivation&lt;/strong&gt;: You can overcome things that may seem boring, or irrelevant if you have a motivation to push thru it. In reality, if you have motivation to do something then those things don’t seem bored or irrelevant. So we really just need to keep our motivation going strong.
We’ve all started something being stoked about it and then when things got hard or felt boring we dropped it and moved on to the next interesting thing. This habit isn’t a bad one, if those things are meant for entertainment. If you are expecting to make a living then there will be parts of your career that aren’t always fun. And even if they are right now doesn’t mean they will be forever. You have to stay motivated to work thru those moments of boredom.
You can keep motivation up if you have good… 👇&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attitudes &amp;#x26; Beliefs&lt;/strong&gt;: If you don’t think you can do something then you won’t. Its that simple. You have to believe you can and have the attitude and confidence that you will. No one wants to help someone with a bad attitude, and people with bad attitudes usually don’t ask for help anyways. Believe you can, do what you can, iterate on that and you WILL.
But I have to admit, don’t just be those people that talk to themselves in the mirror saying:    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can do it. I am great. I can achieve my goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead make a plan. Tell yourself the plan. When things are planned then you fear less, you stress less, you know what to do. Have a plan.    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can learn JavaScript because I’m going to do A, B and C. If A doesn’t work I’ll ask Jared. If B doesn’t work I’ll try D. I have a plan!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/41idZwB0PZYqY/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;In your head&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;TRUE GRIT&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These all combine to something called &lt;strong&gt;GRIT&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grit is a term used in the educational system in reference to: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…individuals who demonstrate perseverance to accomplish educational goals in the face of challenges and setbacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;%5Bhttp://www.instructionaldesign.org/concepts/grit/%5D(http://www.instructionaldesign.org/concepts/grit/)&quot;&gt;Credit: InstructionalDesign.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guess what happens when you try and learn something you’ve never done before? You’re going to fail… a lot. Is that bad? &lt;em&gt;Nope&lt;/em&gt;. Are you not smart because you failed? &lt;em&gt;Nope&lt;/em&gt;. Can you still be successful even though you’ve made mistakes? &lt;em&gt;Hell yeah!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally am okay not knowing everything. I do want to know as much as I can. I do have a hard time not knowing the magic that happens between what I do and the result. But I am not focused on those details until I have to. I personally try and focus on the goal. We’ll get back to that in a minute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A normal developer will not know every array method and coding pattern ever conceived. They don’t code from memory. They look things up. That’s why the documentation exists &lt;em&gt;(or at least we hope there is some documentation 🤞)&lt;/em&gt;. I often go look up those array methods to remember some I’ve forgotten, or to find the best one for the situation. I look up things all the time. Its part of being a professional developer, having to research and read to find the current solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we all just gave up because we didn’t know something, or we tried a fix and it caused more errors, no one would ever do this. That’s why we do debugging. Its why we have code review and why we make tests and continuous integration tests, and on and on. All to check ourselves because we are all fallible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grit is what pushes us thru those hard times to learn from our mistakes and keep trying. We know the journey will have ups and downs and we are okay with that. We enjoy the ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;If Not A Course Then What❓&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of &lt;strong&gt;JUST&lt;/strong&gt; doing courses that run you thru coding concepts &lt;em&gt;(learn letters of the alphabet)&lt;/em&gt;, project based learning has more application, motivation, attention, relevance, and all that good stuff. It creates longer lasting learning thru experiences you will remember. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hardest part of learning is that if you don’t struggle enough then your brain doesn’t think it is worth holding onto. So you forget that spoon fed information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I don’t need to remember how to spell anymore because there are spell checkers on everything I touch. Too easy so my brain doesn’t care to remember the rules. &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;I&lt;/code&gt; before &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;E&lt;/code&gt; except some other time… 🤷‍♂️)*.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your brain needs to feel the pain of trying to make connections. That pain and time is what triggers the brain to hold on to what is going on. Its obviously important, our brain doesn’t waste energy on anything unless it is important. We have to find a way to take learning to code and find that sweet spot of learning brain pains. Not too much or we’ll give up. Not too little or we won’t remember.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/82bcbbdfd2713248e032dd4e7dfc6bec/FindMentor.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Find A Mentor&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mentored projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What fits that? &lt;strong&gt;Mentored projects&lt;/strong&gt;. I know some coding course try and do projects in them but they lack the individualization. Most want you to make a portfolio site. Sorry but I did those and they were terrible and I never used them. I’m not even especially proud of them since I just kinda followed along with their scaffolding way of teaching me. Too easy, not relevant, and looks like everyone else that traced on the dotted lines of their course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/23f0cc9223be87e6178a7be1f70a7394/MentorMentee.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Mentor Mentee&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Try doing the same thing with a mentor. But keep in mind a mentor is there to guide, like the scaffolding, but only when you need a nudge. Most scaffolding is more like video game race tracks. They keep you on the track no matter how far off you try and go. Its the same thing each time you do it and there is no deviating from the course. Mentors are the opposite of that. You decide what you want to do, where you want to go. The mentor points you in the right direction. Helps you here and there. Gives you advice or clarification when you get stuck. You change your mind and want to go in another direction? The mentor can handle that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently I am helping a cousin learn web dev. We’ve gotten thru some basic JavaScript and super basic HTML. I gave him a JavaScript project to learn the basics. Just a choose your own adventure game in vanillaJS. Taught a few things about variables, comparisons, if statements, and confirm prompts. Let him figure it out. I gave him nudge here and there on our weekly meetups. Now he is doing a project to build a website, just html and css. He decides how it is designed, but it has to have links, images, text, 3 sections, etc. Gave him the criteria, which we could change, and let him go at it. In one meeting I showed him how to look at the html and css of other websites in the dev tools. Now he can see what others to do and he can try and mimic them. After we get this done we’ll add in some vanillaJS to his site and get things interacting well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See how he decides what he does. He’s invested in the goal because it is his. He can’t figure something out he can look it up, contact me and I’ll tell him where to look it up or we’ll meet once a week to pair program some things together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trains him to have &lt;strong&gt;GRIT&lt;/strong&gt;. He’s on his own during the week. If he is stuck and doesn’t want to wait 7 days til the next meetup then he has to look things up. He can contact me and I’ll give him things to look up. He has to go thru the brain pain of connecting the dots of this does that, etc. He remembers. He learns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He could give up, but that’s fine. If you can’t make a plan and believe you can do something to the point you need someone to hold your hand each step of the way, then either you lack the will power to do it or it just isn’t for you. Find your passion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/028c647254adac7fe5211ab3171b29e2/TheMoreYouKnow.gif&quot; alt=&quot;The More you KNow&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scaffold learning is required but gets boring fast. Project based learning is more motivating but if you don’t have the grit to continue when you get stuck then it can break you faster. Mentored Projects are the most helpful, applicable and effective way to learn something like coding. It promotes gaining the grit you’ll need for a job and life. Its learning lasts longer, and you have more motivation to finish projects. Find a mentor and get started.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Start Side Projects]]></title><description><![CDATA[I feel like it is important keep doing personal projects to keep learning new things. Keep doing tutorials and using new libraries to find…]]></description><link>https://cjaredm.com/2019-05-29-side-projects/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cjaredm.com/2019-05-29-side-projects/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I feel like it is important keep doing personal projects to keep learning new things. Keep doing tutorials and using new libraries to find what’s good and bad. What’s even better is making things that are useful or someone else might want. I try and find a need and fill it while I learn something new. It gives me motivation to not abandon the project when I get bored or whatever that makes us give up and not finish a project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Find Ideas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Start small&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming up with ideas can be hard. Sometimes I feel like I am suppose to come up with some new business idea that is totally unique and will make me tons of money. Just stop thinking like that, right now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get started build extremely small things that you find useful. Before I really knew what programming was I was into spreadsheets, a lot. I found that Google Drive has its own script language you can use to interact with everything in your drive. Also, I know that every cell phone number has an email specific to the carrier it is on. So I made a spreadsheet with names, birthdays messages and phone numbers with carriers. Then I wrote a script that would check each day at 7 AM if today is someone’s birthday and then email their special carrier email that texts it to them from my google account. I’ll always be the first to message someone &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Happy birthday&lt;/code&gt; on their birthday!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yes, stupid project but easy and fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used a similar setup to make a Lease Ending Reminder script that emails a customer the month before their lease is up on their home. Did that for a friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another friend had a problem with having to fill out a bunch of contracts with contractor/vendor information. Difficult to fill out over and over. So I made a google sheets script that you fill in pertinent info and it takes a template contract, searches for variable names I setup in it and replaces them with the info from the sheet. Easy peasy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Talk To Friends&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice that some projects above came from friends. If you can’t find a need in your life then ask friends. I have come up with great ideas from friends. Found they with something existed, or worked better, or that they didn’t need to do this or that. Pick something and start small. Fix just part of it. Then add to it. Make it better. Add a feature. Keep going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine with a machine shop had an issue tracking orders and parts he is making. Another owns a store but their POS system doesn’t work well. My brother’s business needed an employee and job time tracking system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find a need and fill it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;MVP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start SMALL! Make the minimum viable product (MVP) that someone could use.  Get it in use, put it in someone’s hands. Get feedback. If they aren’t excited about it or have ideas on what they wish it could do then try another idea. The idea is if you make the smallest viable project and people aren’t excited about the possibilities then probably not the best idea to continue. If you have to quit something, the earlier you do it the better. Less wasted time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you want to hear is things like, “Can you get it to do ‘X’?”. When someone sees its use and immediately is hoping it can do more things then it’s a sign they’d use it. If they don’t see anything else they hope out of it, remembering that it is a minimum viable product, then no, you didn’t make it perfectly. They just don’t see themselves using it. Brain turns off and moves on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Complete Something&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re like me, and most other people that code, you’ll likely start lots of projects and never finish them. I have 3 portfolio sites, several other blogs, a movie app, and who knows what else, that I never fully finished. You need to finish things. At least now and then push a product all the way thru. Deploy, ship, whatever. Get it online, or being used. It looks better on a portfolio site as well. Show off things that work and are done. You get the idea. Just finish something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Disproportionate Enthusiasm&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mention I’ve made some small things for friends. I even made a large app for a friend as well. I was stoked, excited, extremely anxious to see how my projects turned out and how much they’d help my friends. Took so much time figuring out the problem, learned something new to solve it, and made it look nice. I give it to my friend to use and…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing. I hear nothing back. I wait. Days go by. Nothing. Why aren’t they telling me how awesome it is? Maybe it is broke? If it were broke the. Why didn’t then tell me so I could fix it? Maybe I should contact them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That all leads to me finding out they ghosted me. Some of them just never responded to me on Facebook again. Some did but said they haven’t used it yet. And after waiting I find they never did use it. Not sure if they were scared to try a new system or thought it was crap. But they never even tried to use it and find out. So frustrating, but very common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Take Away&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make projects! Lots of them. Learn new tech while you do them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make their scope small. Smaller than that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get people using them and get feedback. If they don’t have excited suggestions then quit and move on. Quit projects early or finish them all the way!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complete a project 💯%!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Level Playing Field]]></title><description><![CDATA[Read this with a grain of salt. It’s how I feel, so put your pitch fork down. I know that this isn’t 100% accurate and there are cases you…]]></description><link>https://cjaredm.com/2019-05-29-level-playing-field/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cjaredm.com/2019-05-29-level-playing-field/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Read this with a grain of salt. It’s how I feel, so put your pitch fork down. I know that this isn’t 100% accurate and there are cases you could point at that prove that. Calm down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What do the l33t use?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently was talking to someone I’ve been teaching/mentoring. He was curious about the tools and methods I was showing him on how to make a web page. He assumed these tools and methods were not what the the professionals use, so he wanted to see how I actually do things.
As I was explaining things I realized, maybe not for the first time, that in my field, Frontend Development, we all basically are on the same level playing field. Free tools, open source libraries, all available to everyone, n00bs and l33ts the same (l33t is kinda annoying but it gets the point across).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Code/Frameworks/Libraries&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you want to write a book. What do you need, and is there anything you have to pay for? Well, you need to know the language you’re writing in. You need something to write on to save it… You get the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to write some code or a program or whatever? Do you know the language? Guess what, it’s free. You don’t technically need to pay someone to teach you (though it can help). You don’t need to pay for a certificate or diploma. You don’t need to pay to gain access to the language or documentation on how to use it. It’s free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JavaScript/HTML/CSS, it’s all free and wildly documented all over the internet. You can make a webpage on your computer this moment using any text editor in like two minutes. Using any computer, anywhere. Nothing stopping anyone from doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies build things to help themselves and make it available free to the world. Facebook created React, a library for JavaScript that makes building interactive sites so easy. It’s just JavaScript but with pre-written helpers that you use to speed things up. Technically you could not use React and just use JavaScript to do the exact same thing, but React is easier and faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AirBnB made some JavaScript testing tools. Other people make tools and just publish for everyone to use. Things like EsLint, Prettier, lodash, styled-components. All free for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Editors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several free code editors out there. Do you need one? Nope., but think of the difference writing a paper for school in the basic text editor on your computer versus using Microsoft Word. Word picks up on spelling errors and shows them to you. It has all kinds of editing options and tools specific for writing documents that a normal plain text editor doesn’t have. Same goes for writing code. Technically you could use Vim, the text editor built i to your terminal(command line) on your computer. But that would be hell! So people made editors specific to the languages of code you write in to be able to pick up on mistakes and makes writing faster and easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two big ones are VS Code and Sublime Text. I follow Wes Bos fairly closely, he makes awesome tutorials for JavaScript and React. Because he does tutorials for anyone wanting to learn he wants to make the learning focused on the topic, not the tools, and doesn’t want you to have you to have to pay for extra stuff, which is why he uses VS Code. Very awesome free editor. Very good for paid programming since you can collaborate on  specific project with someone anywhere else in the world. I’ve used it a few times and it has been awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At my work they pay for us to use WebStorm and PhpStorm, editors made by JetBrains. I found that because I have a masters degree my college gives my my .edu email for life. It so happens that the easier way to prove you are a student is to have a .edu email from a big college and that means student discounts or free stuff. I have WebStorm for free with their student program. It does a few things the free editors can’t or haven’t added yet, but VS Code is adding things all the time and can do many things WebStorm can’t. The idea is that, it doesn’t matter though. I don’t need to pay for an editor to code something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Version Control / Backups&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing code is basically just some text documents, usually doesn’t take up a lot of storage on your computer. But, it’s a good idea to keep it somewhere accessible and saved off your computer. You might think of other storage places like DropBox and GoogleDrive but that may eventually cost you as well, as you make a lot of projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In comes places like GitHub and GitBucket and another one… git labs maybe? They use command line interface (CLI) which, you guessed it, is free, called git. Git is used for version control and backing things up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While writing a paper for school have you saved it (KittensPaper) duplicated it and made changes to the duplicate? Then you save that with a different name, like  FinalKittensPaper. You are versioning your papers. Labeling them to help and making duplicates in case one is deleted or corrupted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is what git does,  but for code. It lets you keep the good code on a branch while you make a new branch to try changing that code. If you changes are good you can merge them into the good branch and do it again. And those places like GitHub make it so you can save them online, for free, and show them to others and even have others use your code in their projects. That is where you can download all those libraries I was talking about earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;More than one way to skin a cat&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another awesome thing about programming is that you can create the same thing in a myriad of ways. You can use differe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some ways may be worse/better than others  but that is the idea. You can do it your own way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s amazing that any computer right now could be used to create just about anything in code. You could download some free software, like code editors to make it easier,  but you don’t have to. You could use some libraries other people have written for free,  but you don’t have to. You can save it online for free, but you don’t have to. Right now you can code anything anyone else could code, you could create any website just like any other company or person could, in the world. The only difference is what you and they know about programming languages, which again, you could learn for free online. We developers are on a level playing field. It is awesome to know I can pick up any language I desire at any time. I can make a website just as good as a big corporation, if I had the motivation to. I am the only thing stopping me from learning how.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Deployed!]]></title><description><![CDATA[Finally! I deployed my first ever version 1 project. I’ve started
many projects before but hadn’t pushed thru to get them published and live…]]></description><link>https://cjaredm.com/2019-05-15-deployed/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cjaredm.com/2019-05-15-deployed/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Finally! I deployed my first ever version 1 project. I’ve started
many projects before but hadn’t pushed thru to get them published and live.
This time I did it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/pVM4xuseBY0oIcK2Yp/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;I did it!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What’s the story?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year I had been looking for projects to build, maybe something that would
end up making me money. I asked several family and friends for ideas. I
listened to podcasts about side hustles and these types of projects, or
start-ups. I found that most often they stumble into a good business idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance there was a story of a company making software for plumbers to
find customers. They made a great project and had businesses trying to
use them but many were back out and disappear. They decided to look into how
these businesses were using their product. They found that these small
businesses were struggling with other things and would end up bailing on
their product or not giving it enough attention. Their main issue was
organizing themselves and tracking paper work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The business pivoted and focused on helping small businesses with their
paperwork and tracking. They became a huge success after stumbling onto
the need of their customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what I was trying to do. I found a friend that has a manufacturing
business as a machine shop machining parts from metals. He told me they
have poor order/part tracking and would love to have something simple.
Of course that kind of software already exists but not specific to his
industry that also doesn’t have a ton of things he doesn’t want to pay for.
I worked on it for the last 3-4 months and finally deployed a week ago!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is it?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I built a a customized version of a kanban board specific to his shop/industry.
Pretty simple at first glance, a drag and drop list of todos with specific
machines to do them on and a finished section. I built on that idea and
features as I went. Soon I’ll have analytics built in so that he can look
back and see what employees are working the most efficiently, what customers
provide the most profits, what parts are loosing them money, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/898faa7dec1b1fa978fc2a5422b9d515/4d383/Job_Tracker.png&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
  
  &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
    style=&quot;position: relative; display: block;  max-width: 590px; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
      style=&quot;padding-bottom: 72.2972972972973%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABQAAAAOCAIAAACgpqunAAAACXBIWXMAAAsTAAALEwEAmpwYAAACJElEQVQoz3VRa4vTQBTN/4dlpV8EKyKCCCKKHxZRse52wQ+ya5M2TTOTxySZyfvRpEm6pYuNp4nryooHZrhz7zn3XO5IlmXphBJqEEJnsqxq2mQyubg4nynK2Yezj58/zWRlev718nKqKMr11RUlhOiE9LdUlkUceknsxVFYpWmb57u6brY35fG6wSk2ddlu63aLTNW0VV3n1TqrirKupC5/1/mnXTrqlBfdaNyNnxzGT1+5u5Nl/UjbPDOat97utbMdaZvT1eaxvn/JlyfszYn9/rn4Im3WfpFYZe5UsRetiK9pmWkZIp7+UFXGqYi+zzWF2maYfpuvrlcWiwPNo6pLnURIWb5OsiJO8jjNTIcR03SFCDin+oq7TiC4QQmzzCQMLQS2GQUhM22LGnEYSWmWRVEUx3GSJLZtG4YhhMjznDEnSVHMbMb8ICiKAhnORZIm2LFpmmEYSiiDjSz0jLFezD3Pw+aZ4xyDmazrxBdCxl8sl0EQQAzaUQxDrH14DGLOOZK4h3HQGgLMggAcJO+dUYYADwx/53wE/tnjHAxZmaOapdlCValhDOJ75wdiePq+jwznHrrYtuUwBnNd11F9OPa/zhiXUpSjNE1RxAht21ZV1TQN5jd7/BZTEPtO2DZiOGNPijJHL8SLxQKe+9vbrgdaDHyMIKGT4ziu68IEnojRBR2hH76Q99jv94fDAeK6rt0e4EiH/+Bnjz9Bd4e/Ob8AUy7mkLJwVUQAAAAASUVORK5CYII=&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 100%; margin: 0; vertical-align: middle; position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; box-shadow: inset 0px 0px 0px 400px white;&quot;
        alt=&quot;I did it!&quot;
        title=&quot;&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/898faa7dec1b1fa978fc2a5422b9d515/fcda8/Job_Tracker.png&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/898faa7dec1b1fa978fc2a5422b9d515/12f09/Job_Tracker.png 148w,
/static/898faa7dec1b1fa978fc2a5422b9d515/e4a3f/Job_Tracker.png 295w,
/static/898faa7dec1b1fa978fc2a5422b9d515/fcda8/Job_Tracker.png 590w,
/static/898faa7dec1b1fa978fc2a5422b9d515/efc66/Job_Tracker.png 885w,
/static/898faa7dec1b1fa978fc2a5422b9d515/c83ae/Job_Tracker.png 1180w,
/static/898faa7dec1b1fa978fc2a5422b9d515/4d383/Job_Tracker.png 1195w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px&quot;
      /&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He already started showing his team and will start utilizing it next week.
Because it was a success he brought me another idea of an app to build for
his sisters company that they’ll pay for in full, where this current project
I own and will be charging for monthly and start selling to other shops.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How I Got Started]]></title><description><![CDATA[TLDR I got degrees in things that gave me debt and no real job I loved. Got sick, literally sick, at my job and
decided it was time to…]]></description><link>https://cjaredm.com/2019-04-24-how-i-got-started/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cjaredm.com/2019-04-24-how-i-got-started/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h4&gt;TLDR&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got degrees in things that gave me debt and no real job I loved. Got sick, literally sick, at my job and
decided it was time to figure something out. A friend mentored me and within 4 months I got my first dev job!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/a9327ff8fbcb588a4384b5d10371150a/41099/getajobmeme.jpg&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
  
  &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
    style=&quot;position: relative; display: block;  max-width: 500px; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
      style=&quot;padding-bottom: 66.89189189189189%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAANABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFgABAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAwAE/8QAFgEBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAgAB/9oADAMBAAIQAxAAAAHMwOVjirP/xAAZEAADAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAgMREgD/2gAIAQEAAQUCBct3oeh6nTfMcWja3//EABQRAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABD/2gAIAQMBAT8BP//EABQRAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABD/2gAIAQIBAT8BP//EABgQAAMBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEQEQAx/9oACAEBAAY/AhOMCar/xAAaEAEBAQEBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAABEQAhUTFh/9oACAEBAAE/IVJX1DCTv4XDQXnuURcNUGa6Hyb/2gAMAwEAAgADAAAAEAQ//8QAFhEBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAARBh/9oACAEDAQE/EFyf/8QAGBEAAgMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAERIUH/2gAIAQIBAT8QSnSj/8QAHBABAAIDAAMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQARITFxQWGh/9oACAEBAAE/ELh0jhU6R5NBS0N+6zBSJhQBPkZRAZt8FxSGeytggSXn3P/Z&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 100%; margin: 0; vertical-align: middle; position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; box-shadow: inset 0px 0px 0px 400px white;&quot;
        alt=&quot;Get A Job meme&quot;
        title=&quot;&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/a9327ff8fbcb588a4384b5d10371150a/41099/getajobmeme.jpg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/a9327ff8fbcb588a4384b5d10371150a/a80bd/getajobmeme.jpg 148w,
/static/a9327ff8fbcb588a4384b5d10371150a/1c91a/getajobmeme.jpg 295w,
/static/a9327ff8fbcb588a4384b5d10371150a/41099/getajobmeme.jpg 500w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px&quot;
      /&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Extended History&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent a bunch of money I didn’t have and received a BA in Philosophy. It was fun!
Learned to think more logically and get new perspective… BUT didn’t get me a job. Still fun though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that I got married, had a kid and decided that maybe… maybe I should do something to
make enough money for a family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loved learning and wished I could just keep going to college etc. So what I decided was to
get a master’s degree in Educational Technology, also known as Instructional Design. I’d be
able to create trainings, on everything. So I’d keep learning everything as I made different
things for different people. In fact I did some freelancing for awhile and made trainings for
pest control technicians, an online MBA program in Australia, and a cooking course in an
applied technical college.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUT… alas that didn’t last long. It seems that most people in my cohort in my MEd. program
already had a job in training and were getting education to move up in their company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I spent a bunch of money I didn’t have… again, to get that MEd.

  &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/657f690df4d8e1a36ca27641ffc78917/c08c5/studentloanmeme.jpg&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
  
  &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
    style=&quot;position: relative; display: block;  max-width: 590px; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
      style=&quot;padding-bottom: 104.72972972972974%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAVABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAGAABAQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAMCBQT/xAAVAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAf/aAAwDAQACEAMQAAAB6cIRjtIK9GiNiv/EABoQAAMBAAMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAECAwQQEUH/2gAIAQEAAQUCaqhjqmplRapWTu746Fck2lD0dnj/xAAUEQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAg/9oACAEDAQE/AR//xAAUEQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAg/9oACAECAQE/AR//xAAdEAABBAIDAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAAIRMQMSIDKR/9oACAEBAAY/AiCVbvFs2lk6whEFauueH//EABwQAQACAgMBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEAESExEEGRUf/aAAgBAQABPyF6gkqjos+oAt6ZheGTF7jG0CqIQGrGOFQeR9h5x//aAAwDAQACAAMAAAAQTwCA/8QAFhEAAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAESAh/9oACAEDAQE/EBE//8QAFhEBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEAFB/9oACAECAQE/ENKf/8QAGxABAQADAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAREAITFRQWH/2gAIAQEAAT8QT6O7Q5e4NvNQoPRxC01ERpiCiqgBho39Pc/bfKHt5hhziG6XWOsKu3pwRgTBQK19mf/Z&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 100%; margin: 0; vertical-align: middle; position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; box-shadow: inset 0px 0px 0px 400px white;&quot;
        alt=&quot;Get A Job meme&quot;
        title=&quot;&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/657f690df4d8e1a36ca27641ffc78917/1c72d/studentloanmeme.jpg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/657f690df4d8e1a36ca27641ffc78917/a80bd/studentloanmeme.jpg 148w,
/static/657f690df4d8e1a36ca27641ffc78917/1c91a/studentloanmeme.jpg 295w,
/static/657f690df4d8e1a36ca27641ffc78917/1c72d/studentloanmeme.jpg 590w,
/static/657f690df4d8e1a36ca27641ffc78917/c08c5/studentloanmeme.jpg 640w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px&quot;
      /&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also was working for Apple doing tech support part time. Eventually I did that full time… and grew to… dislike
it, to put it in nice words. It wasn’t hard, but it was boring and I didn’t fit the culture at the time. Wasn’t very
fulfilling (to me that is). I was even getting anxious and stomach aches thinking about going
to work. Dreading it every day. I wanted and needed to get out of there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During all that time I was messing around with spreadsheets and getting deeper and deeper in
Google App Script making silly things. Made a spreadsheet with birthdays that a script would
check every day around 7 AM, and text a special message I wrote to the birthday person. Super
cool, huh? I also made a spreadsheet script for emailing people to remind them when their
lease was ending, their new lease amount and other templated information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Moment&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I was having fun doing that and getting stomach aches before going to work at a dead end
job. Then BAM! My friend Kasey saw what I was doing with spreadsheets and scripts and pushed
me to learn how to code. My wife and I talked about it and I convinced her to go to work full
time while I paid a baby sitter to watch the kids while I learned how to code with some
guidance from my friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About 4 months later I won! I got a job with my friend’s company because I convinced them I
wasn’t a jerk and was a fast learner. YAY! There was probably some other technical stuff I
showed them too, but yeah. I did it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Now&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to now, 2 year later. Learned a ton more. I’m building React Native apps along
with all the other normal, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, PHP, and blah or whatever. I’ve also
found that I want to help other people. I started looking for people to help and mentor into
JavaScript. It has been fun! Met some nice people and have really enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been looking for more ways to help mentor others and keep learning. This blog will talk
about it. Keep checking in.

  &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/80f3fa8695fea9d0a4f6771204458a1b/08ff2/iareprogrammermeme.jpg&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
  
  &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
    style=&quot;position: relative; display: block;  max-width: 474px; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
      style=&quot;padding-bottom: 75%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAPABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFwAAAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAMEBf/EABUBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAB/9oADAMBAAIQAxAAAAFM16ozDRF//8QAGxABAAICAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAgEDABIUITH/2gAIAQEAAQUC8c2XHHO66FrKR48Z/8QAFREBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACH/2gAIAQMBAT8BR//EABQRAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABD/2gAIAQIBAT8BP//EABwQAAIBBQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAhEhIjJhgv/aAAgBAQAGPwJwUteXZdU8lWSjfLIo5PrN2f/EAB0QAAIBBAMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABESExQWFxgfH/2gAIAQEAAT8hSgV5pVmiPvMtBtw3EDVVG/TgaIi8FWeaf//aAAwDAQACAAMAAAAQpw//xAAVEQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEf/aAAgBAwEBPxBT/8QAFhEBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQBB/9oACAECAQE/EJHL/8QAHBABAAICAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQARITFBYYFR/9oACAEBAAE/EEL3EWhqz3x1FqAFg9n3UbVOg5XhLwNxnCva4Yrk3A9N5g5kvM//2Q==&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 100%; margin: 0; vertical-align: middle; position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; box-shadow: inset 0px 0px 0px 400px white;&quot;
        alt=&quot;Get A Job meme&quot;
        title=&quot;&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/80f3fa8695fea9d0a4f6771204458a1b/08ff2/iareprogrammermeme.jpg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/80f3fa8695fea9d0a4f6771204458a1b/a80bd/iareprogrammermeme.jpg 148w,
/static/80f3fa8695fea9d0a4f6771204458a1b/1c91a/iareprogrammermeme.jpg 295w,
/static/80f3fa8695fea9d0a4f6771204458a1b/08ff2/iareprogrammermeme.jpg 474w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 474px) 100vw, 474px&quot;
      /&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hello World! Just figured out how to setup a Gatsby Blog. First attempt at using Gatsby.
I unfortunately tried to do it the hard way, not…]]></description><link>https://cjaredm.com/2019-04-23-hello-world/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cjaredm.com/2019-04-23-hello-world/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hello World! Just figured out how to setup a Gatsby Blog. First attempt at using Gatsby.
I unfortunately tried to do it the hard way, not using the start-blog they have. Got several errors with GraphQL not finding the markdown files… lame!
So I restarted with the starter-blog and it was up and running crazy fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know this still looks like the same start-blog everyone has with Gatsby but I’ll come back and
restyle it later.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>